<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns='http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom' xml:lang='ja'>
  <id>https://gantoin.github.io</id>
  <title>Antoine GAUTHIER</title>
  <updated>2024-03-31T00:18:10+0000</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io" />
  <link rel='self' type='application/atom+xml' href='https://gantoin.github.io/feed.xml' />
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/interface-segregation-principle.html</id>
    <title>Principe de ségrégation des interfaces (SOLID)</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/interface-segregation-principle.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-19T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Le principe de ségrégation des interfaces (ISP) est le quatrième principe de SOLID. Il a été introduit par Robert C. Martin en 1996 dans son article Designing Object Oriented C++ Applications Using the Booch Method.
Qu&apos;est-ce que le principe de ségrégation des interfaces ?
Le principe de ségrégation des interfaces conciste à dire qu&apos;une classe ne doit pas être forcée d&apos;implémenter une méthode dont ...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/liskov-substitution-principle.html</id>
    <title>Principe de substitution de Liskov (SOLID)</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/liskov-substitution-principle.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-11T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Le principe de substitution de Liskov (LSP) est le troisième principe de SOLID. Il a été introduit par Barbara Liskov en 1987 dans son article Data abstraction and hierarchy.
Que sont les principes SOLID ?
Les principes SOLID sont un ensemble de principes de conception logicielle qui permettent de créer des logiciels plus maintenables, flexibles et évolutifs.
Il ne s&apos;agit pas de framework ou de bib...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/open-closed-principle.html</id>
    <title>Principe ouvert/fermé (SOLID)</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/open-closed-principle.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-08T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Le principe ouvert/fermé (OCP) est le deuxième principe de SOLID. Il a été introduit par Bertrand Meyer en 1988 dans son livre Object Oriented Software Construction.
J&apos;aimerais revenir dessus car je pense qu&apos;il est très important de le comprendre et de l&apos;appliquer.
Que sont les principes SOLID ?
Les principes SOLID sont un ensemble de principes de conception logicielle qui permettent de créer des l...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/single-responsibility-principle.html</id>
    <title>Principe de responsabilité unique (SOLID)</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/single-responsibility-principle.html" />
    <updated>2023-09-07T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Le principe de responsabilité unique (SRP) est le premier principe de SOLID. Il a été introduit par Robert C. Martin en 2003 dans son livre Agile Software Development, Principles, Patterns, and Practices.
J&apos;aimerais revenir dessus car je pense qu&apos;il est très important de le comprendre et de l&apos;appliquer.
Que sont les principes SOLID ?
Les principes SOLID sont un ensemble de principes de conception l...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/kafka-avro.html</id>
    <title>Make your Kafka bus more robust with Apache Avro &amp; Confluent Schema Registry</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/kafka-avro.html" />
    <updated>2023-01-26T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>In this article, you will learn how to use Apache Avro and Confluent Schema Registry to make your Kafka bus more robust.
Introduction
Apache Kafka is a distributed streaming platform. It is used to publish and subscribe to streams of records, similar to a message queue or enterprise messaging system. Kafka is often used as a data bus to connect different systems and applications. It is a very power...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/landoop-fast-data-dev-M1.html</id>
    <title>How to run &apos;landoop/fast-data-dev&apos; on Mac M1?</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/landoop-fast-data-dev-M1.html" />
    <updated>2023-01-19T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Hey guys!
I was following a lecture about Kafka Schema Registry when I suddenly had to run Landoop and a bunch of tools with Docker on my Mac.
I met this error after running this Dockerfile:
Setting advertised host to 127.0.0.1.
runtime: failed to create new OS thread (have 2 already; errno=22)
fatal error: newosproc

After a few minutes of searching, I understood that&apos;s because I ran it on my M1 a...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/chat-gpt-api.html</id>
    <title>How to use ChatGPT API in your Java application?</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/chat-gpt-api.html" />
    <updated>2023-01-08T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Hi guys 👋 I&apos;m sure you enjoy using chat GPT to produce, optimise, or translate code from any programming language to Java.
Today I&apos;ll show you how to use OpenAI ChatGPT API with Java, it&apos;s pretty easy.
1. Register for an API key
First, you&apos;ll need to register for an API key by going to the OpenAI API page. Follow the instructions to create an account and obtain an API key.
2. Enter a credit card i...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/Twitch-API-OAuth2-Spring-Security.html</id>
    <title>Configure Twitch API OAuth2 provider on a Spring Security app</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/Twitch-API-OAuth2-Spring-Security.html" />
    <updated>2023-01-04T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Hi guys, I&apos;m working on a SaaS to manage Twitch Clips of broadcasters:
- Create vertical Clips automatically for TikTok, Youtube Shorts, etc.
- Create compilation for clips to easily make best-of
So, I had to plug my Spring Security app into the Twitch OAuth2 provider and it was not easy...
How to do that?
Prerequisites
Before you begin, you need to have the following:


A Twitch account and a regi...</summary>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://gantoin.github.io/blog/Umbrel-Nextcloud-mobile-app.html</id>
    <title>How to plug your Umbrel&apos;s Nextcloud into the official Nextcloud mobile app?</title>
    <link></link>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://gantoin.github.io/blog/Umbrel-Nextcloud-mobile-app.html" />
    <updated>2022-08-21T00:00:00+0000</updated>
    <summary>Why you could want to do that?
You could want to use the Nextcloud app to make saving your phone data easier or to get documents from your cloud easily (without a Tor browser, connect via onion etc.).
Why is it not possible natively?
It&apos;s impossible to connect the Nextcloud app to a onion address, you need a clear-net URL. We will use Tailscale to solve this problem.
What is Tailscale?
Tailscale is...</summary>
  </entry>
</feed>
